Christopher W. F. Parsonson

scholar.google.com/citations?user=2Vw7d64AAAAJ&hl cwfparsonson@gmail.com

SUMMARY

5+ years experience in ML/AI/networking research and development. Proven success developing state-of-the-art algorithms, open-sourcing high-quality research code, and publishing, reviewing, and winning awards in top outlets such as AAAI, NeurIPS, ICML, JLT, and OFC. Demonstrated ability to apply AI/ML solutions to real-world problems.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python, MATLAB, PyTorch, TensorFlow, DGL, PyTorch Geometric, W&B, Hydra, TensorBoard, Ray, RLlib, Gym, Pandas, NumPy, SciPy, Scikit-learn, PySCIPOpt, CVXPY, PuLP, Jupyter, Neovim, VSCode, Git, Linux, tmux, Sphinx, Docker, LTEX

EDUCATION

University College London (UCL), PhD

2019 - Present

Thesis: 'Computer Network Optimisation with Artificial Intelligence and Optics', EEE Dept., Optical Networks Group

- Authored 10+ publications in leading AI/ML and networking outlets (AAAI, OFC, JLT, etc.)
- ICML outstanding reviewer award (top 10%), NeurIPS reviewer, UCL 3MT competition winner
- Developed state-of-the-art reinforcement learning/graph neural network/swarm/evolutionary algorithms
- Deployed open source software package for custom reproducible network traffic generation

University of Cambridge (Gonville & Caius College), MRes

2018 - 2019

Integrated Photonic & Electronic Systems Engineering, **Distinction**

Projects in (1) 3D computational holography for VR & AR displays (2) signal optimisation with swarm algorithms
 Imperial College London, MEng

2014 — 2018

Materials Science and Engineering, First-Class Honours

• Top 5% of class (out of 120 students), awarded Morgan Advanced Ceramics prize for academic excellence

EXPERIENCE

Visiting Researcher, The Alan Turing Institute, London

2022

• Developed graph neural network and reinforcement learning algorithm for partitioning distributed deep learning jobs, achieving $\sim 60\%$ higher cluster throughput than prior state-of-the-art. Paper under peer review

Research Scientist Intern, InstaDeep Ltd., London

2021 - 2022

- Developed graph neural network and reinforcement learning algorithm to solve NP-hard mixed integer linear programming problems $3-5 \times$ faster than prior work, enabling practical application at scale
- One paper published in AAAI'23, one under peer review

ConceptionX Deep Tech Startup Programme, U.K.

2021 - 2022

- · Explored commercial potential of deep geometric learning in logistics and information security domains
- One of 16 teams selected (from 70+ initial groups) to pitch to 400+ investors and industry leaders at demo day

Lecturer & Teaching Assistant, UCL & UCL-Consultants, London

2019 - 2022

- AI Masterclass for DSTL, Machine Learning MSc, Applied Machine Learning Systems, Programming & Control Systems, Cloud Data Centres & Edge Computing, Python Programming, Mathematical Modelling & Analysis
- Leadership roles included: Lecturing, examining, tutorial demonstrations & supervisions, course & exam design

Research Engineer Intern, VividQ Ltd., Cambridge

2018 — 2019

- Developed and deployed method to expand 3D display size by $2\times$ without compromising quality

Research Engineer Intern, Dyson Ltd., Bristol

2017

- Worked in thermodynamics research team. Conceptualised and demonstrated method to increase heat sink efficiency by 50%. Allocated \$20k budget to set up and manage new suppliers and contracted researchers
- Participated in 2017 Hackathon, taking third place

Engineers Without Borders Challenge Finalist, U.K.

2017

- Competitive 20-week national competition to develop engineering solutions for Bambui, Cameroon
- Won entry out of 4,600+ applicants to finals where presented to 200+ engineers and 18 judges
- Finished 3^{rd} , placing in top 0.1% of applicants

Internships at Cambridge Nanosystems, Polygelco, and Ubisense